# Kaishan Ding

835 Cotati Ter #6, Sunnyvale CA, 94085 CELL (415) 988-5396 • E-MAIL dingkaishan@gmail.com Authorized to work in the U.S.

# **Personal Summary**

IOS Application Development with two years providing quality developing and designing on mobile apps that solves real-time issues. Extensive experience designing great user interface then implement them on to iOS applications. Outstanding organizational and problem-solving abilities with strong background in project coordination, intermediate-level skills of Swift, great communication skills.

## **Education**

University of Washington-Seattle campus Seattle, WA

Bachelor of Science in Human Center Design & Engineering

Path: Human-Computer Interaction

Courses: Data structure, Abstraction, Encapsulation, Algorithms, Object-oriented

programming, DBMS, Data analytics, iOS mobile development, User-Centered Design

## **Skills**

Software Tools: XCode, Blender, Linux, GitHub, Azure, MATLAB, Microsoft Office Suite.

Programming Languages: Swift, Java, Python, SQL, noSQL

Languages: English, Chinese

## **Personal Projects**

**iOS** App: MarKetUp (available on App Store)

Develop a stock market simulator by utilizing APIs and Swift Sep 2019-Nov 2019

Build this iOS App from design to publishment on App Store

iOS App: TiPong & Pursuit Light (not available now)

• Develop two fun 2D iOS games

May 2017-Oct 2017

Accomplish reaching 500+ downloads on App Store

• Utilize the knowledge of physics and object-oriented programming comcepts

# Work Experience

#### Orlando O Spencer I, Ins

IOS Developer Intern

Dec 2019-Mar 2020

Seattle, Washington

Sep 2018-Jan 2022

Major GPA: 3.72/4.0

- Build iOS native UI and working with Designers
- Practice skills with UIKit, PDFKit, Swift, and some third-party libraries
- Layout development plans for certain fields of the application, such as menu, login module, etc.

#### **GAC R&D Center Silicon Valley**

Jun 2019-Aug 2019

Software Engineer Intern

Sunnyvale, California

- Model 3D real-world buildings and locate them in an autonomous vehicle simulator
- Partner with Uber ATG team and visualize GAC's self-driving data on a web-based toolkit to detect patterns and metrics easier

#### Links

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/kaishan-ding/

GitHub: github.com/dks333

INTERESTS: Traveling, Stock Market/Options/ETF, Gym, Basketball, Soccer, Snowboarding, and Puzzles (Escape Rooms)